♪ It seems today that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a... Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
♪ Family Guy 11x06 ♪ Joe's Revenge
乔的复仇
翻译&注释: wudixny 校对&压制: zurica @familyguy贴吧字幕组
晚上好 我是Tom Tucker
Good evening. I'm Tom Tucker.
新闻插播 在逃通缉犯Bobby"衬衫"Briggs
This just in: Wanted fugitive, Bobby "The Shirt" Briggs,
犯罪时以一直穿着衬衫而臭名昭著
notorious for always wearing shirts while committing
在潜逃了15年后
his crimes, has finally been caught
终于被逮捕了
after 15 years on the lam.
引用一位警方发言人的话
A police spokesperson was quoted as saying,
"咄 我是个傻警察
"Duh, I'm a dumb cop.
我想要给Tom Tucker开张罚单"
I like to give Tom Tucker a ticket."
我都要41岁了好么
I was going, like, 41.
天啊 我不敢相信
Oh, my God, I don't believe it.
他们终于抓住那杂种Briggs了
They finally got that son of a bitch, Briggs.
你认识那家伙
You know that guy?
我当然认识
You're damn right, I do.
Bobby Briggs就是那个让我待在轮椅上的人
Bobby Briggs is the one who put me in this wheelchair.
他们抓到他了
They got him.
他们终于抓住他了
They finally got him.
天啊 Joe 你没事吧
Geez, Joe, you okay?
给 用我的手绢吧
Here, use my handkerchief.
又湿又冷啊
It's wet and cold.
呃 是啊 因为是我的手绢嘛
Well, yeah, it's my handkerchief.
我整天用它擤鼻子的
I've been blowing my nose in it all day.
等等 Bobby Briggs是弄残你的人
Wait a minute, Bobby Briggs is the one who crippled you?
你一直是跟我们说你是从房顶上摔下来的
You always told us you fell off a roof
是在和鬼精灵的一次打斗中
during a fight with the Grinch.
破坏圣诞的绿皮精灵 S01E05提到过
我撒谎了
I lied.
我撒谎是因为我对实际情况感到羞愧
I lied because I was ashamed of the real story:
因为我让一个穷凶极恶的罪犯逃掉了
that I let a vicious criminal get away.
怎么回事
What happened?
那是1996年
Well, it was 1996.
Briggs是普罗维斯登斯东部最大的海洛因贩子之一
Briggs was one of the biggest heroin dealers
在差不多靠近河边的地方
east of Providence, which is mostly just open water,
但我仍然在卧底跟踪他的行动
but still, I'd been undercover, tracking his operation
持续了六个月 最终得到了他的信任
for six months and had finally gained his confidence.
我已经基本上收集到了足够的证据
I had almost gathered enough evidence
一劳永逸地解决Briggs
to put Briggs away for good,
但我知道一段坦白的录音
but I knew a taped confession
会让这案子更加稳妥
would make the case a slam dunk.
这样我们就能更上一个台阶了
This is gonna take us to the next level.
我们就能上各种辣妹了
We're gonna be banging so many hot chicks
穿着露脐牛仔裤的那种
with jeans up to their navels.
Bobby Briggs 你还真是对海洛因在行
Bobby Briggs, you're really good at heroin.
这里有多少海洛因 Bobby Briggs
How much heroin is here, Bobby Briggs?
你为什么用那种口吻
Why are you talking like that?
你带窃听器了吗
Are you wearing a wire?
噢 你死定了 Joe Swansonson
Oh, you're dead, Joe Swansonson.
我的卧底名字叫Swansonson
My undercover name was Swansonson.
别激动 Briggs
Easy, Briggs.
你杀了警察的话 就等着终身监禁吧
You kill a cop, they'll put you away forever.
那你就准备好下半辈子
Then get ready to spend the rest of your life
做个老婆声音很恼人的瘸腿残废吧
as a lame gimp with an annoying-voiced wife.
他见过Bonnie
He'd met Bonnie.
Briggs跑了
Briggs got away,
我坐上轮椅后就再也没见过他
and I've been in this wheelchair ever since.
我喜欢你能讲一个
I like that you can tell me a story
从醉蚌酒吧开始到摩天轮才结束的故事
starting at the Clam and ending on a Ferris wheel.
没错 非洲的人还在挨饿
Yeah, people are starving in Africa,
我却在嘉年华
and I'm at a carnival
和我的好哥们一起享受美好的夜晚
with my best buddies on a beautiful night.
谢谢主的赐福
Blessings. Blessings.
这么说 Joe 你一定感觉很棒吧 他们终于
So, Joe, it must feel great to finally
了结了Bobby Briggs这个案子
have some closure with Bobby Briggs.
没错
Yeah.
知道么 昨晚是我15年来首次
You know last night was the first time in 15 years
没有在梦中掐过Bonnie
I didn't strangle Bonnie in my sleep?
好吧
Okay.
哎 爸 这个你一定要看看
Hey, Dad, you're gonna want to see this.
重新关注我们的重大新闻
Again recapping our breaking news,
长期在逃犯Bobby Briggs已从警察的羁押下逃走
longtime fugitive Bobby Briggs has escaped from police custody.
他目前下落不明
His whereabouts are currently unknown.
Briggs逃走的新闻首先出现在德莱门多电视台
News of Briggs's escape first broke on Telemundo,
美国第二大西班牙语电视网
如果你真相信的话
if you can believe that.
(西语)逃了 逃了 逃了
Escapo! Escapo! Escapo!
据报道 Briggs是在监狱开放日期间逃走的
Briggs reportedly escaped during a prison open house,
此类活动未来很可能会被取消
an event that will most likely be canceled in the future.
不 不要 我不敢相信啊
No, no! I can't believe it.
噢 别担心 他们会把他抓回来的
Oh, don't worry, Joe, they'll get him back.
不会的
No, they won't!
他们花了15年才抓到他
It took 15 years to catch him.
现在是个出去的好时机
Well, this seems like a good time to be heading out.
我本来就该回去了的
I should be getting back anyway.
我把Rupert留给个保姆照看了
I left Rupert with a sitter.
呃 你知道东西都放在哪儿
Well, you know where everything is.
冰箱里的东西请自便
Feel free to help yourself to anything in the fridge.
这里的骗子先生可以吃布丁或者冰淇淋 但不能都吃
And Mr. Con Man here can have pudding or ice cream, not both.
头儿 能谈谈么
Chief, can I have a word?
可以 但首先 你得承认
Yeah, but first, you have to agree
双性恋男人和
there's a huge difference
同性恋男人是有很大差别的
between bisexual men and homosexual men.
- 当然了 头儿 - 非常谢谢你
- Sure, Chief. - Thank you. Huge.
什么事
What is it?
头儿 其实我来是因为我希望你
Well, Chief, I'm here because I want you
能让我加入Briggs的案子
to put me on the Briggs case.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
别这样啊 头儿
Come on, Chief!
我知晓Briggs的一切
I know everything about Briggs.
我是唯一能抓住他的人
I'm the only one who can catch him.
不行 Swanson 这案子和你牵涉太多
No, Swanson, you're too close to the case.
我让Grant和Casey来处理这案子
I'm putting Officers Grant and Casey on it
因为他们和这案子的联系不大
because they're so far from the case,
他们完全不在乎
they don't care about it at all.
- 嗨 头儿 - 嗨
- Hi, Chief. - Hi.
这不公平
This isn't fair!
Swanson 你知道你的任务
Swanson, you know your assignment.
你给我抓来那个在唐恩都乐店子里
You get me the guy who's been rubbing his butt
美国连锁快餐店
到处摩擦屁股的家伙
all over Dunkin' Donuts.
有什么需要吗
Can I help you?
不犯法 不犯法
Not illegal. Not illegal.
出示法律呀 不犯法
Show me the law. Not illegal.
嘿 Joe 听着 我知道你对
Hey, Joe, look, I know you're down
Briggs这件事挺难过 这也让我很不好受
about this Briggs thing, and that kind of bums me out,
所以我买了个帕斯曲奇给你
so I got you this Cookie Puss.
一个用冰激凌蛋糕做的人物
是不是很搞笑
Isn't that funny?
看那奇怪的鼻子呀
Look at that weird nose.
我觉得你的鼻子才怪呢
I think your nose is weird.
伙计们 我想说 我...
Guys, I'm telling you, I...
我不认为我能继续让Briggs
I just don't think I could live with Briggs
再逃窜个15年
on the lam for another 15 years.
那你为什么不做点什么
Well, why don't you do something about it?
我什么也不能做 头儿不允许
I can't do anything about it. The chief won't let me.
Joe 如果他们找不到这家伙
Joe, if they don't find this guy,
你下半辈子会难受得像被活活吞掉
it's gonna eat you alive for the rest of your life.
你必须要亲自出手
You got to take matters into your own hands.
你必须要追捕这家伙
You got to go after this guy.
但这违反了警察的规章制度啊
But that's a breach of police protocol.
这和你是不是警察无关
This isn't about you as a cop.
这是关于作为男人的你
This is about you as a man.
来吧 你怎么说
Come on, what do you say?
Quagmire和我会帮你将这家伙绳之以法的
Quagmire and I will help you bring this guy to justice.
Peter 我是怎么和你说
Peter, what did I say
关于你"自愿"我参加这种鬼事的
about you volunteering me for (bleep)?
好 我们干吧
All right, let's do it!
如果你们打算这么干
Well, if you're gonna do it,
你们就需要一个特别会伪装的人
you're gonna need someone who's very good at disguise.
是谁在说话
Who said that?
我很想和你们一起去 但我不能
I'd love to go with you, but I can't.
我要装成礼物台
I'm supposed to be the gift table
参加明天一个酒吧成人礼
at a Bar Mitzvah tomorrow.
好吧 如果我们要追踪Briggs
All right, if we're gonna go after Briggs,
从这里开始就挺不错
this might be a good place to start.
我花了之前的15年
I've spent the last 15 years
来收集他的信息
gathering information on him,
全都在这里了
and it's all here.
他犯下的所有罪行 他所有的合伙人...
Every crime he's committed, every associate he's...
噢 看啊 Briggs曾经是全国县级资浅游泳代表队的
Oh, look, Briggs was All-County JV swimming.
呃 我对这些屁事不感兴趣
Well, I don't just focus on the negative.
Joe 你25岁的儿子和你的小女儿共用一间房
Joe, your 25-year-old son and your baby daughter share
这样你就能空出一个《美丽心灵》里的变态房间么
a room just so you can keep a weirdo Beautiful Mind room?
2001年电影 其中也有一间类似的房间
这是不是太奇怪了
Isn't that a little bizarre?
然后我们从那家伊拉克人的头骨里把子弹挖了出来
And then we dug the bullets out of that Iraqi family's skulls
这样他们就不能追踪到我们了
so they couldn't be traced back to us.
今天我看见一个气球
MAN'S VOICE: Today, I saw a balloon.
FBI的Briggs档案里说这么多年与他来唯一
Briggs' FBI profile says the only relationship
还有联系的就是一个叫Tanya的脱衣舞女了
he's maintained over the years is with a stripper named Tanya.
税务记录显示她正在
Tax records show she currently works
一家亚特兰大城的俱乐部工作
at a club in Atlantic City.
所以那是我们的第一站
So that's our first stop.
那家俱乐部有身体接触么
Is there touching at the club?
我-我不知道 Peter 也许吧
I-I-I don't know, Peter. Maybe.
好 很好 很好
Okay, this is good, this is good.
那我肯定要把我的惹火牛仔裤也带上
I'll be sure to pack my blemming jeans.
听着 谢谢你答应
Hey, listen, thanks for agreeing
在我离开时照顾"公主"(意大利语) Lois
to take care of Principessa while we're gone, Lois.
这是我们的荣幸
It's our pleasure.
她看上去是只可爱的小猫
She looks like a nice kitty.
呃 小猫
Uh, kitty?
Lois 她可是纯种波斯猫
Lois, she is a purebred Persian.
我可以追溯她的血统到埃及艳后养的猫
I can trace her lineage to the cats kept by Cleopatra.
那你告诉我该怎么做就行了 Glenn
Just tell me what I need to do, Glenn.
好 首先 她的肠道非常活跃
Well, first, she has a very active bowel.
在用纸尿布方面不要太吝啬了
You can't be too generous with the baby wipes.
要从前面到后面这样擦拭就像你对自己一样
Stroke front to back like you would on yourself.
否则你就会把屎弄到她的生殖器里
Otherwise, you're smashing feces into her genitals.
另外 她很容易受惊
Also, she's very skittish,
所以你只能这样摸她
so you have to touch her like this.
我现在要抚摸你了哦
I'm going to touch you now.
可以吗
Is that okay?
看到我是怎么做的了
See how I'm going?
慢慢的 慢慢的
Slowly, slowly.
哦 那存于你体内的神秘感
Oh, the mysteries you keep inside of you.
Quagmire 快点 我们走
PETER: Quagmire, come on, let's go.
好吧 我想我们该出发了
All right, I guess we're off.
嘿 伙计们 看看
Hey, you guys, check out the look
我这么做时Lois的表情
on Lois's face when I do this.
Peter!
收拾干净 你个蠢货
Clean that up, you idiot!
爱你哟
Love you.
[进入康涅狄格州]
哇 最终永远铐住Briggs的时候
Boy, it'll be satisfying to finally slap the cuffs
我一定会非常满足的
on Briggs once and for all.
你们有没有驶过一座小镇 然后产生
Hey, you ever just drive through a town and wonder,
- "到底是谁住在这地方"的想法 - 一直如此
- "Who the hell lives here?" - All the time.
看看这里 我是说 怎-怎么回事啊
Look at this place. I mean, what-what's going on?
这有个成年人在买柠檬水
There's an adult with a lemonade stand.
那家中国餐馆还留着
That Chinese restaurant still has the sign
以前汽修工的招牌
from when it was a mechanic.
我可不想在换消音器的地方
I don't want to eat lo mein
吃着拌面
where they were just changing mufflers.
那家阿比快餐店的楼上有间公寓
There's an apartment above that Arby's.
北美的快餐连锁店
窗户边还有玩具
With toys in the window.
有人在那上面建立了一个家
Someone has built a life up there.
真是一团糟
What a mess.
我告诉你 开国元勋们一定会
I'm telling you, the Founding Fathers would be
无比失望地看到他们的国家变成现在这样
very disappointed in where their country ended up.
呃 过去也没那么好的
Eh, it wasn't so perfect back then, either.
所以我对你们说
And so I say unto you,
自由之子们 自由的人们将不会再
sons of liberty, no longer will free men
生活在大型食肉鸟类的枷锁之下
live under the yoke of giant predatory birds.
它们尖叫 向下俯冲 偷走我们的家畜
Shrieking, swooping down, stealing our livestock.
这里怎么回事
What's going on in here?
没-没什么 呃 就是在抱怨英国人
N-Nothing, uh, just bellyaching about the British.
给我继续回去孵蛋
Get back to warming those eggs.
好了 就是这里
All right, this is the place.
看看能否找到Briggs的马子
We got to see if we can find Briggs's girl.
嘿 我们在找一个叫Tanya的脱衣舞女
Hey, we're looking for a stripper named Tanya.
她今晚在么
She here tonight?
嗯 她在香槟室接活呢
Yeah, she's working the Champagne Room.
跟我来
Follow me.
嘿 Quagmire 你 呃...
Hey, Quagmire, you, uh...
你以前来过亚特兰大城么
you ever been to Atlantic City before?
来过一次 20年前 怎么了
Once, about 20 years ago. Why?
- 好耶 - 好耶
- All right! - All right!
嘿 你是Tanya么
Hey, are you Tanya?
是啊 你是谁
Yeah. Who are you?
找Bobby Briggs的人
A guy who's looking for Bobby Briggs.
他在哪
Where is he?
我不认识任何Bobby Briggs
I don't know any Bobby Briggs.
就算我认识 我也不会告诉你
And even if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
你在撒谎
You're lying!
Joe 让我来
Joe, let me handle this.
我知道如何和她们沟通
I know how to communicate with strippers.
我只需一支舞足矣
All I need is one dance,
然后我就知道她所知的一切了
and I'll know everything she knows.
你有空来只舞么
You free for a dance?
当然
Sure.
我需要消息
I need information.
我被我爸猥亵了
I was molested by my dad.
这我知道 我要别的消息
I know that. I need other information.
我要你告诉我哪能找到Bobby Briggs
I want you to tell me where I can find Bobby Briggs.
不要嘛 你知道我不能泄漏
Come on, you know I can't give out
客户的私人信息的
a client's personal information.
好吧 那我要用瓦肯人阴道感应能力了
All right, I'm gonna have to do the Vulcan V-Meld.
恶搞《星际迷航》中的Vulcan Meld瓦肯人心灵感应
他住在海洋大道2820号
He lives at 2820 Ocean Boulevard,
公园对面 二号公寓
across from the park, apartment two.
好姑娘
Atta girl.
好了 现在朝自己嘴里吐口水
Okay, now spit in your own mouth.
这地方太酷了
This is a cool place.
噢 有Quagmire先生的猫在这儿真是好啊
Boy, it sure is nice having Mr. Quagmire's cat around.
我得说猫可比狗好多了
I got to say, cats are so much better than dogs.
你那只是个宽泛的说法
Well, that's kind of a broad statement.
是真的
It's true.
好吧 给我展示下猫比狗强的一方面
Okay, show me one way in which cats are better than dogs.
好吧 呃 首先
Well, okay, uh, for one thing,
它们总会用脚着地
they always land on their feet.
看好了
Watch.
那又怎样 没什么大不了 狗也会这个
So? Big deal. Dogs do that, too.
来 对我重复你刚做的事
Here, go ahead, do what you just did, but with me.
嗷 天啊
Ow! Oh, my God!
噢 我的脖子 嗷
Oh, my neck! Ow!
上帝 Brian
Oh, my God, Brian!
别碰我 别碰我 去叫人 噢
Don't touch me! Don't touch me! Call somebody! Oh!
我们需要一张
We need one of those boards
给足球运动员的那种板 嗷
they use for football players! Ow!
嘿 怎么回事
Hey, what's going on?
没什么
Nothing.
我刚发现为何猫比婴儿好了
I just figured out why cats are better than babies.
你那只是个宽泛的说法
Well, that's kind of a broad statement.
好了 海洋大道2820号 就是这儿
Okay, 2820 Ocean, this is it.
好 二号公寓
All right, apartment number two.
我们只要开锁就行了
We'll just pick the lock.
什么 这是什么
What? What is that?
让我们用自己的眼睛来看
Let's use our eyes to see.
啊 这家伙有甜麦片
Aw, this guy has sugar cereals.
他妈妈一定很酷
His mom must be so cool.
他还有个垃圾压缩机
And he's got a trash compactor.
完全压实了
It compacted it all.
简直屌爆了
That is so boss.
啊哈 我们又见面了 Briggs
Aha! We meet again, Briggs.
喔 喔 喔 你谁啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Who are you?
Joe Swanson.
谁
Who?
等等 你...你不记得我了
Wait, you... you don't remember me?
我潜伏进了你的海洛因团伙
I infiltrated your heroin operation.
我们还一起看过《现实的创痛》
We saw Reality Bites together.
1994年本斯蒂勒自导自演的电影
伙计们 我找到他了
You guys, I found him!
他朝这边跑了
He went that way!
妈的 是Lois
Damn it. That's Lois.
我不接的话 她会杀了我的
If I don't get this, she's going to kill me.
嗨 甜心
Hi, sweetie.
嗯 一切都好
Yeah, everything's great.
当然 我想你
Of course, I miss you.
呃 超市的西芹怎么会都卖完了呢
Well, how does the supermarket run out of parsley?
我和你一样愤慨
I'm as angry as you are.
Peter 我要掉下去了
Peter, I'm going to fall!
看来你无处可逃了
It looks like you're out of roof.
妈的 没路过去了
Damn it. There's no way across.
小蛛蛛 你能用网把我们荡过去么
Spidey, can you swing us across with your web?
不 我不能荡你过去
No, I can't swing you across.
而且我叫蜘蛛侠 不叫小蛛蛛
And it's Spider-Man, not Spidey.
我很确定听人这么叫过你
I'm pretty sure I've heard people call you Spidey.
没错 好朋友
Yeah, close friends.
- 你叫什么 - Peter
- What's your name? - Peter.
嘿 Petey 为我做事
Hey, Petey, do stuff for me.
- 噢 我不喜欢这样 - 是吧 你不喜欢
- Oh, I don't like that. - Yeah, you don't like it.
你就是个肥屌丝 而我是他妈的蜘蛛侠
And you're a fat nobody, and I'm (bleep) Spider-Man,
你觉得我怎么想
so how do you think I feel?
他要跑了 把我从边上扔下去
He's getting away. Guys, drop me over the side!
你疯了么 Joe
Are you crazy, Joe?!
你会死掉的
That fall will kill you.
只要我用腿着陆就不会
Not if I land on my legs.
小心
Heads up.
我现在抓到你了 Briggs
I got you now, Briggs.
移开那公交车
Move that bus!
恶搞真人秀《彻底改变之家庭再造》
享受你们的新家吧
Enjoy your new home.
他跑了 伙计们
He's gone, you guys!
我本来抓到他了
I had him!
那是我们仅有的机会
That was our one chance!
没关系的 Joe
It's all right, Joe.
你没什么好惭愧的
You got nothing to be ashamed of.
你是个很棒的警察
You're a great cop
有着非常杰出的职业生涯
with a very distinguished career.
你还抓到了那个杀死
You caught that guy who was killing
所有菲律宾女孩的家伙
all those Filipino girls.
是啊 但这很重要
Yeah, but this was important!
他毁了我的一生
This was the guy who ruined my life.
这变态对我来说就是全部
The one perv who meant everything to me.
如果我抓住他
If I caught this guy,
我才能睡个踏实觉
I'd finally be able to sleep at night.
妈的
Damn it!
哦 谢天谢地 警察
Oh, thank God. Cops.
噢 太好了
Oh, good.
你们仍然能抓住Briggs
You guys can still catch Briggs.
他朝那边跑了
He's headed that way.
我们不是来抓他的
We're not here for him.
我们是来找你们的
We're here for you guys.
你们现在因妨碍
You're under arrest for interfering
警方调查被捕了
with a police investigation.
什么
What?
是啊 搞毛呢
Yeah, what the hell?
你们应该在外面去逮捕真正的罪犯
You should be out there arresting the real criminals.
就像挥舞弹簧刀的白人
Like switchblade-wielding white guys
出现在影视剧中 他们还不说人话
from movies and TV who don't talk like people talk.
别怕 老妈子
Easy, mama.
交出钱包 还有所有
Hand over that purse, and everything
很酷的玩意 你的懂
will be real cool, you dig?
伙计们 你得让我们离开这儿
Guys, you got to let us out of here.
真的罪犯要逃走了
The real criminal's getting away.
是啊 那坏蛋要逃掉了
Yeah, the bastard's making a break for it,
就像南美洲一样
just like South America.
嗯
Hmm.
那边有好多黑哥们儿
Lot of black guys over there.
嘿 兄弟 你去哪
Hey, man, where you going?
恶搞了古代冈瓦纳大陆的分裂
我会回来的 我就回来
I'll be back. I'm coming back.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
为何警察要逮捕我们
Why would the cops arrest us
而不是去追捕Briggs呢
instead of going after Briggs?
Flannigan 慢着
Flannigan? Wait a minute.
那个就是在Briggs逃跑的15年里
That's one of the corrupt cops who helped harbor Briggs
一直包庇他的坏警察
while he was on the lam for 15 years.
这些家伙可麻烦了
These guys are bad news.
天啊
Oh, my God.
他们准备把我们怎么办
What are they going to do to us?
我不准备待在这儿等答案了
We're not going to stick around to find out.
Joe 把你的手铐放我腿上
Joe, hold your handcuffs over my lap.
那是啥玩意儿
What the hell is that?
瑞士军鸡
Swiss Army penis.
哇 Quagmire 屌爆了啊
Wow, Quagmire. That's incredible.
Peter?
你这是用更结实的金属做的
Yours are made of a stronger metal.
我们要用乙炔喷灯鸡鸡了
We're going to have to go with the acetylene torch penis.
不...不要直视
Don't... don't look right at it.
我的性病让它烧的更亮
My STDs help it burn brighter.
钥匙就在点火孔里 走
The keys are in the ignition. Let's go!
我告诉过你搜那人的鸡鸡的
I told you to search that guy's penis.
每个人你都这么说过
You say that about everybody.
- 吔 我们成功了 - 但我们跟丢了Briggs
- Yeah, we did it! - But we lost Briggs.
我们现在要怎么找到他呢
How are we going to find him now?
我们没有任何线索啊
We got nothing.
呃 我不知道是否有用 但我找到了
Well, I don't know if it helps, but I found
这个号码 就在他厨房的电话机旁
this number next to the phone in his kitchen.
我本来想留着做
I was saving it 'cause I was going to make
一本和你们一起旅行的剪贴簿的
a scrapbook of the trip for you guys.
让我看看
Let me see that.
这是墨西哥华瑞兹市的区号
This is the area code for Juarez, Mexico.
他准备越境
He's trying to get over the border!
- 你真这么想 - 绝对的
- You think so? - Definitely.
这里只有一条路通往华瑞兹市
There's only one road into Juarez,
而且穿过埃尔帕索
and it goes through El Paso.
美国得克萨斯州西部城市 其实两市间有4个过境站
我们要先到埃尔帕索
We got to get to El Paso.
Joe 你怎么会知道
Joe, how do you know
墨西哥华纳兹市区号的
the area code for Juarez, Mexico?
我去那瞧过一个干细胞医生
There was a stem cell doctor I went down there to see.
但他只是在我腿上擦了什么洋葱辣汁
He just rubbed, like, salsa on my legs.
嘿 你们没穿制服
Hey, you're not in uniform.
你们是警察么
Are you guys cops?
他们发现我们不是警察了
They know we're not cops!
[亚特兰大城 国际机场]
好了各位 下一班
All right, guys, the next flight
飞往埃尔帕索的飞机40分钟后起飞
to El Paso leaves in 40 minutes.
但是Briggs在我们前头啊
But Briggs is ahead of us.
他会不会已经到那儿了
Won't he already be there?
不会的 他绝不会冒险通过机场的
No, he'd never risk going through an airport.
有太多警察和摄像头
Too many cops, too many cameras,
还有保安了
too much security.
我不确定 Joe
I don't know, Joe.
有时候保安真的很懒散的
Sometimes the security's pretty lax.
我是说 我上次乘的飞机就被基佬打劫了
I mean, the last plane I was on got gay-jacked.
这班飞机要飞去迈阿密
This plane's going to Miami!
嘿 Lois
Hey, Lois?
嘘 安静 brian
Shh. Quiet, Brian.
妈正在沙发上小睡呢
Mom's taking a nap on the couch.
是啊 瞧 她睡着了
Yeah. And look, she fell asleep
猫也在她胸口上睡着了
with the cat right on her chest.
是不是很萌啊
Isn't that cute?
喵
Meow.
我以为你睡着了
I think you're dreaming.
没有
No, I'm not.
傻逼猫
Stupid cat!
[美国/墨西哥边境 就在前方]
天 真他妈热
God, it's so damn hot.
嘿 我有个点子
Hey, I got an idea.
我们来做滚烫沥青版天使吧
Let's make scalding asphalt angels.
"做天使"指躺在雪地中用身体蹭出天使状的印痕
嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
二级的烧伤 一级的娱乐
Second-degree burns; first-degree fun.
天 我们还要在这儿站多久
Geez, how long we got to stand out here like this?
直到Briggs过来
Till Briggs comes through.
知道么 我正在想这事儿 Joe
You know, I was thinking about that, Joe.
如果Briggs是开车过来 那差不多要2000英里了
If Briggs is driving here, that's like 2,000 miles.
至少得要好几天啊
It's going to be at least a couple of days.
嗯 我想你说的对
Huh. I guess you're right.
那我们这两天在埃尔帕索干嘛呢
Well, what are we going to do for two days in El Paso?
有一个奇卡诺民俗节
There's a Chicano heritage festival.
奇卡诺指20世纪中期以后墨西哥裔美国人
没门
No way.
凯西与阳光合唱团会到场演出
KC and the Sunshine Band is playing.
美国乐团 曲风包含放克 R&B和迪斯科
为什么
Why?
或者我们可以参观潘兴故居
Or we could visit the Pershing House
约翰潘兴于1914年在那里
where John Pershing took control
(1860-1948)美国著名军事家 陆军特级上将
接管了第八军旅
of the Eighth Army Brigade in 1914.
- 那是他的床 - 是
- So, that's his bed? - Yes.
- 那是他的桌子 - 是
- So, that's his desk? - Yes.
- 那是他的灯 - 是
- So, that's his lamp? - Yes.
- 那是他的梳妆台 - 是
- So, that's his dresser? - Yes.
- 那是他的窗子 - 是
- So, that's his window? - Yes.
- 那是他的地板 - 是
- So, that's his floor? - Yes.
哇
Wow.
你那有什么情况 Quagmire
What do you got there, Quagmire?
是Briggs么
Is that Briggs?
不 这家伙没问题
No, this guy's clean.
那就让他过去啊 为什么拖这么久
Well, send him through. What's the holdup?
阔边帽 沙球
Sombreros! Maracas!
陶瓷维尼小熊玩偶
Ceramic Winnie the Pooh dolls!
现在就买吧 各位
Get 'em now, folks!
这些东西你去墨西哥就买不到了
You're not going to find this stuff in Mexico!
快点啊 前面怎么回事啊
Come on. What's going on up there?
Briggs.
妈的 他要跑了
Damn it! He's getting away!
这次不会再让你跑了 你这杂种
You're not going to get away this time, you son of a bitch.
请不要杀我
Please, don't kill me.
我还没结婚
I'm not married.
我的生活很棒的
My life is awesome.
我等这一刻已经15年了 Briggs
I've waited 15 years for this moment, Briggs.
你知不知道
Do you have any idea what it's like
每天要把自己弄进轮椅的感觉
to have to lift yourself into a wheelchair every morning?
在你老婆眼中只是半个男人
To have your wife look at you like you're half a man?
可以优先停车
To get preferential parking?
和头等乘客一起先登机
To board a plane early with the first-class people
还有金卡会员
and gold card members?
好吧 也不是那么糟
All right, it's not all bad.
但我不会杀了你
But I'm not going to kill you.
我可不是像你一样的禽兽
I'm not an animal like you.
那你准备干吗 逮捕我
So, what are you going to do, arrest me?
不
No.
我不会逮捕瘸子
I don't arrest cripples.
另外 你被捕了
By the way, you're under arrest.
我说这话只是因为它很酷罢了
I only said that last thing 'cause it seemed cool.
天啊 太厉害了
Oh, my God, that was so awesome.
我全看到了
I saw everything.
你就像这样...
You were all like...
然后Briggs像这样...
And Briggs was all like...
然后你再像这样...
And then you were all like...
然后Briggs的腿像这样...
And then Briggs's legs were like...
模仿"吃豆人"
噢 日 他死了
Oh, crap, he's dead.
我想他血流光了
I think he bled out.
我一定是打中他股动脉了
I must have hit the femoral artery.
啊 那我们就把他踢到墨西哥吧
Ah, just kick him into Mexico.
伙计们 你们所做的我无以为谢
Guys, I can't thank you enough for what you did.
你们为我冒了生命危险
You risked your lives for me,
没有你们我是做不成这事的
and I couldn't have done it without you.
嘿 好朋友不就是该这样吗
Hey, that's what pals are for.
是啊 谢谢让我
Yeah, and thanks for letting me
朝Briggs的尸体开了几枪
fire a few rounds into Briggs's corpse.
那是我这几年来感到最有力量的时候了
That was the most powerful I've felt in a couple years.
好了 你们帮我
Well, you guys helped me
了结了我此生的仇怨
finally have some closure in my life.
我感觉就像一个崭新的人 就像我重生了
I feel like a new man-- like I'm reborn.
Joe 你裤腿里有血流出来了
Joe, you have blood just pouring out of your pant leg.
嗯 我有个蛋在河里爆了
Yeah, I had a ball blow in the river.
翻译&注释: wudixny 校对&压制: zurica @familyguy贴吧字幕组